# PAUL M. VERA

# MERN DEVELOPER

#### GITHUB.COM/PAUL88VERA | PAULVERA.COM

SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS 7822I 210-501-927I | PAUL88VERA@GMAIL.COM

### **SUMMARY**

Web Developer with over 5 years of industry and educational setting experience in front-end development, and a new insight to back-end development after completing a coding bootcamp with the University of Texas at Austin. Passionate about learning new technologies, frameworks, and creating functional applications.

#### SKILLS

HTML5
CSS/SASS
Bootstrap
Python
Javascript/TypeScript
JQuery
Node.js

Express.js

JSON Web Token/Bcrypt

Restful API

MongoDB

React.js/Vite

SQL/MySQL/GraphQL

Linux/Apple/Windows

Cloud Services/AWS
Git/GitHub
MVC Framework
VSCode/Dreamweaver
Adobe Creative Suite/Figma/XD
WordPress/PHP

## PROFESSIONAL WORK HISTORY

## Senior Web Developer

# Transcendental | San Antonio, TX | May 2023 - Current

- Develops multiple medium-scale websites, 34 43 pages, in a timely manner.
- Created Python automation to convert (jpeg, jpg, and png) images to webp format.
- Increased revenue by 200% for over 4 dental practices after website was created.
- Produces web designer' vision through development.
- Communicates with clientele to maintain website productivity and functionality.
- Maintains intense deadlines using project management applications such as Clickup, Asana.
- Maintains production by using WPEngine environment control.
- Develops custom templates to decrease development time and increase quality proficiency.
- Creates dynamic attributes to change information throughout the website at once.
- Proficient in maintaining brand themes and colors.
- Implements UI by developing JavaScript animations using SVG, PNG, and other media.

#### Web Developer

#### Community Bible Church | San Antonio, TX | Jun 2022 - May 2023

- Conduct UX/UI Research interviews and questionnaires to modernize the current website.
- Present UX/UI Research findings to ministry leaders and administer updates to site.
- Manage multiple large scale website daily (1000-2000 viewers daily, 8000-9000+ on Sundays).
- Developed webpage/website mockups and prototypes using Adobe XD and Figma.
- Produce and manage data for events, web pages, and users in Shelby Arena DB and WordPress DB.
- Use Git/Github for version control on current projects.
- Lead meetings to discuss webpages/websites that meet the ministry leaders' needs.
- Administer daily website maintenance such as updating PHP versions, plugins, and events in the database.
- Communicate and Partner with third-party contractors to develop other large scale sites needed by ministry leaders.
- Develop, create, and publish interactive mobile responsive webpages/sites within a short amount of time.
- Code with VSCode and use File Transfer Protocols to get/push WordPress pages.
- Design animations and interactions for all platform outlets such as web, email, video, and social.

# Freelance Web Developer & IT Technician VERAfied Creations | San Antonio, TX | Feb 2016 - Current

- Communicated with business owners to create websites based on their given criteria and ideal future company growth/expansion.
- Developed mockups and prototypes using Adobe XD and Figma.
- Created custom end-to-end React is sites that used Node is, Express is, MongoDB, and JSX.
- Helped owners implement new domain setup.
- MVC framework was used to create reusable code and to increase productivity.
- Variations of elements were created for A/B Testing to find the best results for user experience.
- Created logos and implemented content marketing strategies that significantly gained new leads.
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO) processes such as increasing website speed, targeting keywords, and creating backlinks were used to get a
  better website ranking to increase website popularity.
- Landing Pages were designed to compel users to sign up for newsletters or for more information on the specific topic.
- · Opt-In Email Marketing was implemented to gain user information to add to our mailing list for further discounts.
- Developed authorized admin logins using JSON Web Token and MySQL, NoSQL, or GraphQL depending on type of website wanted by owners.

# Information Technology Teacher

# Southwest Legacy Highschool | San Antonio, TX | Aug 2021 - May 2022

- Developed Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills aligned curriculum for Computer Science I, Computer Maintenance, Principles of IT Fundamentals, and Web Design courses for secondary students.
- Taught secondary students the latest trends and practices in UX/UI development which include CSS animations, dark mode implementation, contrasting typography, and addition of gradients.
- Bootstrap 5 was introduced after CSS concepts were obtained to quicken production.
- Provided a two-week bootcamp for Responsive Web Design that includes HTML and CSS basic coding structure, element usage and definitions, best practices and personal knowledge in graphic design, and layout design using flex or grid to create responsive pages.
- Created responsive front-end websites from wireframes using web applications such as Figma and Adobe XD.
- JavaScript was used to create event listeners for specific Document Object Models or (DOM) to create a sense of user interaction.
- Implemented and trained students using Python language curriculum provided by Amazon called ProjectSTEM.
- Visual Studio Code editor UI was taught to secondary students for the creation and implementation of their coding projects.
- My responsibilities included building TEKS aligned curriculum, managing the Cybersecurity Program, sponsoring the CyberPatriot Club, and Proctoring End of Year (EOY) CompTIA certification exams, (CompTIA ITF+).

### Creative Designer

## Codeup | San Antonio, TX | Mar 2021 - Aug 2021

- Created digital and print designs such as vector assets, billboard compositions, social media campaigns, mailing print campaigns, brochures, and merchandise for the company.
- Maintained the WordPress CMS for the entire company and created new web pages upon request.
- Developed UX/UI driven web pages for employees and students such as graduation web pages that showcased their completed final group
  projects, embedded specific social media hyperlinks leading to students for possible employer hire, and created employee information pages for
  company wide announcements/knowledge.
- JavaScript was used to add conditional logic to certain pages to add video players, user interaction animations, and embedding Google Maps
  API's using additional plugins for WordPress (Insert Headers and Footers by WPBeginner the plugin installed).
- Created embedded hyperlinks in PDF documents that were distributed to Codeup sponsors and affiliates.
- Resized, converted, and manipulated various medium to fit company distribution needs using Visual Studio Code, Canva, and the Adobe Creative Suite.
- Updated UX/UI design and responsiveness on webpages upon request.
- Communicated with Marketing Director to and Marketing Team during daily AGILE meetings to maintain, and meet production dates.

## Web Design & Animation Teacher

# New Braunfels High School | New Braunfels, TX | Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

- Developed Texas Essential Knowledge and Skills aligned curriculum for Web Design and 2D/3D Animation courses for secondary students.
- Taught secondary students design principles and elements of design in order to create well balanced and user-friendly end products.
- Bootstrap 4 was used for in-class competitions to create visually appealing web pages quickly.
- Adobe Dreamweaver UI was taught for the creation and implementation of coding projects.
- Adobe Animate, Adobe Illustrator, and Autodesk Maya were taught to render 3D animations and create vector assets for webpages to produce
  a unique aesthetic for their websites.
- Provided research tips, understanding of documentation, and usage of Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe Animate, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro, and Adobe XD software.
- Direct students won awards in Business Professional of America competitions: 1st Place National winners for the 3D Animation in 2017, 2nd Place National for 3D Animation in 2018, and 1st Place State Graphic Design winner in 2019.
- My responsibilities included building TEKS aligned curriculum, managing Business Professionals of America organization (BPA) finances for NBISD, and coordinating state competitions for the Business Professionals of America organization (BPA) at NBISD.

# **PROJECTS**

#### CIRCULATE: github.com/paul88vera/CirculateAPP | Full-Stack Developer

Circulate is going to be a Progressive Web Application to search for restaurants within the city of San Antonio.

- Created a database using Prisma and Node.js
- TypeScript was used for error handling and object development
- Created a service worker and manifest, json to create a downloadable application on any device.
- Technologies Used: Vite, React.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Vercel, and Prisma

#### CBC CHAMPION PLAZA: championplaza.com | Front-End Developer

Champion Plaza is a front facing website to showcase information on an ongoing architectural development.

- Communicated effectively to create a website to a customers specifications
- Implemented UX/UI Design methodologies to create a user friendly design
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, AWS Route53, and AWS S3

#### INPSIRE DENTAL: <u>firestoneinspire.com</u> | Front-End Developer

Inspire Dental is a dental practice located in Firestone, Colorado.

- Implemented End-to-End design using WordPress and Elementor
- Manage technical edits, feature requests, and plugin updates
- Domain management
- Accessibility widgets were implemented
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, Elementor, Figma, and Adobe Photoshop

#### INSPIRED DENTISTRY: inspireddentistrypc.com | Front-End Developer

Inspired Dentistry is a dental practice located in Florida.

- User Interactions were implement throughout the site
- Domain management & Website Hosting on WPEngine
- Developed custom animations for service cards
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, Elementor, Figma, and Adobe Photoshop

# **CURRENT PROJECT**

#### CLIENTAPP: github.com/transcendentalagency/clientapp | Full-Stack Developer

ClientApp is an analytics dashboard that will show a prior year of Google Analytics data. (Currently in Private Repository)

- Authentication was implemented using AuthO. Administrative roles are currently being developed.
- Current technologies were used in development
- Developed User based application with mobile first design
- Technologies Used: Vite, React.js, Node.js, TailwindCSS, AuthO, BiginAPI

### **EDUCATION**

Certification of Completion UT Code | University of Texas at Austin Bachelor of Fine Arts in Video Production | The Art Institute of San Antonio

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

CompTIA ITF+ | CompTIA EC-12 242 Technology Applications Certification | Texas Education Agency Warrior Leader Certified | U.S. Army